POCHOLO TAN Software Engineer

An IT professional with 17+ years of history working with multinational clients. A creative individual who maximizes given opportunities, having earned expertise in being a self-taught learner of new technologies, with an eye for detail and efficiency in mind.



https://www.linkedin.com/in/pocholo-tan-66b05270 https://github.com/pochiman

TECHNOLOGIES

•	OS:	Linux (RHEL, Ubuntu), AIX, HP-UX, Solaris, macOS	8 years
•	Database:	Oracle SQL, Firebase NoSQL	4 years
•	IDE:	Visual Studio Code	1 year
•	Automation:	Grunt, Gulp	1 year
•	Code Analysis:	ESLint, Flow, Prettier	1 year
•	Code Review:	Git	1 year
•	Version Control:	Git/GitHub	1 year
•	Integration:	CircleCl	1 year
•	Issue Tracking:	Zendesk, ServiceNow	1 year
•	Cloud:	AWS	1 year
•	Container Orchestration:	Docker, Kubernetes	1 year
•	Job Scheduler:	Tidal, AutoSys, Cron	1 year
•	Virtualization:	Docker	1 year
•	Testing tools:	Jest, Mocha	1 year
•	Languages:	JavaScript, Python, Bash shell scripting	4 years
•	Frontend:	Vue, React, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Django	1 year
•	Backend:	Node, Express, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes	1 year
•	Volume Management:	Veritas NetBackup in Linux, AIX LVM, Linux LVM	1 year
•	Hardware:	IBM POWER systems, HP x86	8 years
•	Storage:	SSD, SAN and NAS based	8 years
•	Middleware:	JBOSS, Tomcat	4 years
•	Webserver:	Apache HTTP/tomcat	4 years
•	Monitoring:	BMC Patrol, Netcool	1 year
•	Interests:	GraphQL, TensorFlow, Machine Learning	1 year

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Engineer LogDNA

JAN 2019 – DEC 2019 Toronto, Canada

- Worked directly with Ops & Engineering to provide amazing customer service and technical support for on a rotating on-call team schedule.
- Took ownership of customer issues while managing expectations and seeing them through to resolution.
- Developed an understanding of the platform and how customers used it on a day to day basis to design a well thought of, clear and polished UI using Vue.js, providing an engaging and delightful user experience.
- Expedited the development of UI components in addition to creating a responsive web design layout using CSS Grid, Flexbox and Sass for our web-based application.
- Optimized the application for maximum speed and scalability in keeping with our coding best practices.

- Provisioned and maintained testing environments using Jest and Mocha while picking up on written, tested and reviewed code for our integration codebases.
- Communicated across teams to discover busted stuff, if any, with our Node.js backend to make sure we write the right code in the right place, helping make the right decisions given the information we have.
- Provided ongoing maintenance, support and enhancements of our integrations.
- Investigated and improved performance in resource-constrained or high-throughput use cases.
- Researched on new integrations and next generation of existing integrations.
- Wrote and maintained awesome Slite documentations and run books.
- Worked closely with product management, design and internal teams to understand the needs of our customers and guickly iterate these to build features.
- Performed change management tasks on live production environments to implement features on the frontend side of our web application.
- Collaborated closely with engineering, operations and product teams to develop UIs that provide a consistent experience across all web browsers and operating systems.

Technical Systems Analyst RBC

SEP 2018 – DEC 2018 Toronto, Canada

- Worked as a Technical Systems Analyst for the Digital Cheque Processing and Channels Applications team, responsible for software solutions supporting our business sponsors, Personal & Commercial Banking, Cap Markets, Wealth Management and Treasury Services etc. The team is dedicated to providing cost effective software solutions, delivered at an accelerated development pace. This team builds and maintains the NCR suite of products for digital cheque processing for branches, commercial clients, mobile clients, internal business units and clearing exchange with Canadian and US direct and indirect clearers.
- Designed technical solutions that meet business requirements and PLC deliverables including component reusability, data sharing and security.
- Provided estimates on activities/tasks required to perform design, coding and unit testing, improving accuracy over time.
- Coordinated design phases for medium projects; identifying, tracking and resolving technical issues.
- Detailed technical specifications based on Project Office objectives for PLC and documentation.
- Participated in walkthrough reviews of all technical specifications, programs and unit test plans.
- Coordinated the implementation, planning and execution of project plans.
- Coordinated and provided input to the DBA in modifying existing database structures.
- Wrote unit test plans and provided coordination and support of testing using different tools.
- Performed database/disaster recovery testing for individual databases.
- Performed performance tuning to improve performance of the application.
- Provided on-call support for applications, databases, etc.
- Completed technical documentation and training materials.

Application Developer IBM Solutions Delivery

JAN 2015 – JUN 2018 Manila, Philippines

- Built and deployed code in dev, test and prod environments.
- Deployed SQL database changes using Oracle SQL Developer.
- Repurposed and replicated AIX- HP-UX, Linux boxes for new projects.
- Resolved ITSM tickets, threshold alerts using CLI on AIX, HP-UX, Linux environments.
- Implemented migrations on production environments and acted as weekend on call support.
- 24x7 Mission critical support for frontend Java applications on Apache and JBoss App Servers.

• Developed and maintained APIs written in XML as well as Python and Bash shell scripts for automation using Vi, employing an Agile approach.

Unix Administrator Emerio

AUG 2014 – JAN 2015 Manila, Philippines

- Monitored Red Hat Linux 6/7 dev, test and prod environments.
- Managed VMware enabled infrastructure, user account creation and patch deployments.
- Resolved Service Manager tickets while handling incident requests, change tasks and escalations.

Programmer III Bangko Sentral Ng Pilipinas

FEB 2014 – AUG 2014 Manila, Philippines

- Analyzed and drafts all PFO Business Functional Specifications.
- Developed and maintains existing office applications in relation to PFO operations.
- Analyzed statistical information derived from the databank and outputs customized reports as requested by different sections to aid them in carrying out their assignments.
- Acted as the point person for the PFMS SAP and BESS system modules and coordinates with ITSS on existing programs that require correspondence until issue resolution.

L3 Unix Production Support Specialist Tata Consultancy Services

SEP 2013 – FEB 2014 Manila, Philippines

 Worked as a L3 Unix Production Support Specialist providing assistance to developers using applications such as Git, GitHub and Bitbucket for version control, Confluence for enterprise knowledge management, Jira for issue tracking and project management purposes, Jenkins for continuous integration and delivery, Ansible for configuration management, Unix CLI for server admin, Crucible for code reviews and Fisheye for revision control and creating repositories.

Unix Applications Engineer NYSE Euronext

MAR 2013 – SEP 2013 Manila, Philippines

- Resolved Service Now tickets within SLAs.
- Fulfilled Veritas NetBackup and data extracts as required by business teams.
- Utilized Tidal Enterprise Scheduler and/or AutoSys for workload automation.
- Monitored the daily start-up and shutdown of test and production applications.
- Managed production outages and performs root cause analysis with various groups.
- Provided monitoring and support of financial markets dealing with equities, derivatives and commodities using a Trade Registration System and IBM Websphere MQ Explorer.
- Provided health checks using BMC Patrol for applications on test and production servers after other groups have completed system migrations and major changes.

Oracle Database Administrator Accenture

FEB 2012 – FEB 2013 Manila, Philippines

- Created new database users as required and maintains system security.
- Optimized performance and implements database backup and recovery.

- Resolved Service Now tickets, threshold alerts and provides on call support.
- Developed Bash shell scripts and sets up cron scheduler jobs in Linux environments.
- Facilitated Oracle 10g/11g migrations and database changes for development, test and production.

Service Desk Engineer Accenture

MAY 2008 – JAN 2012 Manila, Philippines

- Handled BMC Remedy tickets in accordance with ITIL incident management processes.
- Remotely facilitated the installation, configuration, maintenance and optimization of multi-user Unix and Windows systems and resolves errors and virus infections through registry edits, proprietary scans and uninstalling / reinstalling current patches.

Technical Support Representative Teletech

NOV 2005 – DEC 2007 Manila, Philippines

• Resolved CRM tickets by providing first level technical assistance with emphasis on LAN and Wireless networking devices for clients calling in to discuss issues they are having with their DSL internet service.

Customer Service Associate 3 eTelecare Global Solutions

MAY 2002 – MAY 2005 Manila, Philippines

- Answered inquiries and fulfills foreign currency orders for credit card members.
- Processed replacements for lost traveler's cheques via a risk-based analysis system.

Certifications & Training

- Applied Data Science with Python Level 2 from IBM
- Python for Data Science from IBM
- Oracle Certified Expert, Oracle Real Application Clusters 11g and Grid Infrastructure Administrator
- Oracle Database 11g Performance Tuning Certified Expert
- Oracle Database 11g Administrator Certified Professional
- Oracle Database 11g Administrator Certified Associate
- Oracle Certified Expert, Oracle Solaris 10 Network Administrator
- Oracle Certified Expert, Oracle Solaris 10 Security Administrator
- Oracle Certified Professional, Oracle Solaris 10 System Administrator
- Oracle Database 11g Advanced PL/SQL from Oracle
- Unix Administration and Shell Scripting from Accenture
- Oracle Database 11g Administration I and SQL Fundamentals I from Accenture
- Remote Systems Optimization and Malware Removal from Accenture
- PC Hardware Troubleshooting from Teletech

Education